Hey, don't take a detour here.
Hei, jangan mampir ke sini, dong.
Let's just go home already.
Ayo pulang saja.
Geez, I give up.
Astaga, aku menyerah.
I'm starving.
Aku lapar.
I have no money.
Bokek juga.
If only that rug were still okay.
Andai permadaninya masih bagus.
Dammit.
Sial.
This is…
Ini…
"Save me!"
"Tolong aku!
"The monster inside me is about to burst out!"
Monster di dalam diriku akan keluar!"
There are two individuals within Johan.
Ada dua kepribadian dalam diri Johan.
So, what you're saying is…
Jadi, maksudmu,
When you stopped by the warehouse,
saat kau datang ke gudang itu,
that Asian guy and the arsonist were already in a scuffle.
pria Asia itu dan pelaku sedang bergelut.
Then, the Asian guy noticed you were there and ran off.
Lalu, pria Asia itu kabur saat melihatmu.
Is that right, Ms. Anna Liebert?
Benar begitu, Nona Anna Liebert?
Yes.
Ya.
Well, the culprit is a member of the far-right
Pelakunya anggota kelompok sayap kanan ekstrem.
and has turned himself in, saying the flames were for a festival of race.
Dia menyerahkan diri dan pembakaran itu demi festival rasnya.
Your personal references hold up,
Penjaminmu juga tepercaya,
so we can stop for today.
jadi hari ini cukup sampai di sini.
Does that mean I can go home now?
Berarti aku boleh pulang?
Yes.
Ya.
And also, the people of that district
Satu lagi, warga di distrik itu
called that Asian by the name of Dr. Tenma.
memanggil pria Asia itu dr. Tenma.
Do you know anything about him?
Apa kau tahu sesuatu tentangnya?
I don't know anything.
Aku tak tahu.
What do you think?
Bagaimana menurutmu?
Given her outfit, maybe she was trying to engage in prostitution in that district.
Dengan pakaian begitu, mungkin dia ingin memangkal di sana.
No.
Bukan itu.
What?
Apa?
I'm talking about Dr. Tenma.
Maksudku dr. Tenma.
At first, people from the Turkish District called the Asian man by that name.
Awalnya, warga di distrik Turki memanggil pria Asia itu dr. Tenma.
But when we began investigations and said he was a suspected serial killer,
Tapi saat penyidikan dan kita menyebutnya tersangka pembunuhan berantai,
they all would say the same thing.
jawaban mereka semua sama.
They'd say, "I don't know this man."
"Aku tak kenal pria ini."
I acted as your guarantor.
Aku jadi penjaminmu.
Mr. Rosso.
Pak Rosso.
Have you been well, Anna?
Kabarmu baik, Anna?
I've been worried about you.
Aku khawatir.
You disappeared so suddenly.
Tiba-tiba saja kau menghilang.
Are you done changing?
Sudah ganti baju?
Yeah, that kind of outfit looks better on you.
Ya, pakaian seperti itu lebih cocok untukmu.
That look before didn't suit you.
Baju tadi tak cocok untukmu.
Come. I bet you're hungry.
Ayo. Kau pasti lapar.
Eat some food.
Makanlah.
Are you not eating, Mr. Rosso?
Pak Rosso tak makan?
I ate before I came here.
Aku tadi sudah makan.
I'll just have a coffee.
Minum kopi cukup.
Come on. Eat.
Ayo. Makanlah.
Yes. Thank you for the food.
Ya. Selamat makan.
What is it?
Ada apa?
Just like always, you put in five spoonfuls of sugar.
Seperti biasa, kau menambahkan lima sendok gula.
Of course I did.
Tentu saja.
Coffee doesn't taste good unless it's sweet.
Kopi tidak enak kalau tidak manis.
You finally smiled.
Kau akhirnya tersenyum.
You came to interview for a job, yet your face looked so gloomy.
Kau datang wawancara kerja, tapi wajahmu muram.
Is it so strange to put in a lot of sugar?
Apa aneh memasukkan gula sebanyak ini?
Anna, um…
Namamu Anna…
I, um…
Itu…
You're hired, of course.
Kau diterima.
It's a no-brainer.
Sudah jelas.
If a beauty like you works here,
Jika ada gadis cantik kerja di sini,
our business will boom like crazy.
toko kami akan ramai.
But…
Tapi…
But?
Tapi?
You should smile a bit more.
Kau harus lebih banyak tersenyum.
Your beauty will go to waste.
Kecantikanmu nanti sia-sia.
Thank you very much.
Terima kasih banyak.
I'll work hard.
Aku akan bekerja keras.
You don't have to strain yourself.
Jangan memaksakan diri.
We're an Italian restaurant in a rural town.
Ini restoran Italia di kota pinggiran.
Keeping busy won't amount to much.
Menyibukkan diri pun tidak ada bedanya.
Go around the counter.
Lewat situ.
Okay.
Baik.
I'll bring out the food here.
Makanannya kuletakkan di sini.
You'll take it to the customer.
Lalu kau hidangkan ke pembeli.
Used plates are placed on the right side of the counter.
Piring bekas diletakkan di sisi kanan meja.
Wine goes here, and glasses are on this shelf.
Anggur di sini, gelas di sini.
There's wine above the counter too.
Di sini juga ada rak anggur.
Tickets with people's orders go here.
Pesanan pembeli dikaitkan di sini.
There's wine above the counter,
Ada rak anggur di rak atas,
and glasses are there.
gelasnya di sana.
This is the water.
Ini air putih.
Okay.
Baik.
Hello.
Permisi.
Come on in.
Silakan.
Welcome.
Selamat datang.
I'm starving.
Aku lapar.
What?
Wah.
Nice to meet you.
Salam kenal.
I'm Anna.
Aku Anna.
"Nice to meet you"? Hold on.
"Salam kenal?"
You can't possibly be the waitress at a place like this, right?
Mustahil kau pramusaji di kedai seperti ini.
What?
Apa?
What do you mean, "a place like this"?
Apa maksudnya "kedai seperti ini"?
Anna is, without a doubt, a waitress here starting today.
Anna pramusaji baru di sini.
I'll do my best.
Mohon bantuannya.
Are you serious?
Kau serius?
Well, isn't that something.
Wah.
What's this?
Apa ini?
Anna, can I have a carbonara?
Anna, pesan karbonara, ya!
Anna, I'll have a bolognese.
Anna, aku pesan bolognese.
Anna, can you come and pour me some water?
Anna, bisa minta air minum?
Yes, right away.
Ya, mohon tunggu.
That's one carbonara and a bolognese.
Satu karbonara dan satu bolognese.
Got it!
Baik!
Thank you for waiting.
Maaf menunggu.
Thanks.
Terima kasih.
Here's vongole and rigatoni.
Vongole dan rigatoni.
Fettuccine is ready too.
Fettuccine juga siap.
Got it!
Baik!
Hey, Rosso.
Hei, Rosso.
Where'd you snatch this cute girl from?
Di mana kau menculik gadis manis ini?
Don't say "snatch," or people will get the wrong idea.
Jangan bilang "menculik", nanti reputasiku rusak.
Anna.
Anna.
I'll take you to a much nicer restaurant than this.
Aku mau mengajakmu ke restoran lebih bagus.
How's tonight?
Malam ini bisa?
Hey!
Hei!
Lay a hand on our star and you won't get off easy.
Awas kalau macam-macam dengan primadona kami.
Hey, that crybaby Rosso is acting pretty valiant.
Hei, si Cengeng Rosso sok berani, tuh.
Anna, that guy was crying the other day while watching a movie on TV at my place.
Anna, pria itu tempo hari menangis saat menonton film di rumahku.
Shut up.
Berisik.
Another order for squid ink risotto.
Risoto tinta cumi satu lagi.
Wow, they're showing Summertime.
Wah, mereka menayangkan Summertime.
The old cinema is showing Summertime, see?
Lihat, bioskop lam menayangkan Summertime.
Isn't it nice?
Enak, ya?
Frankfurt has so many movie theaters.
Frankfurt punya banyak bioskop.
It was on TV the other day.
Tempo hari ada yang tayang di TV.
It was a real tearjerker.
Filmnya benar-benar mengharukan.
Have you watched it?
Pernah menontonnya?
I haven't.
Belum.
I see.
Begitu.
The film takes place in the Italian city of Venice.
Filmnya berlatar di Venesia, kota di Italia.
Venice is a port city from medieval times
Venesia adalah kota pelabuhan sejak abad pertengahan
and is called the City of Water.
dan dijuluki Kota Air.
The city was originally built on a lagoon.
Kota itu awalnya dibangun di atas laguna.
That is why a canal runs through the city.
Karena itu di tengah kota ada kanal.
I'd love to show you Venice sometime, Anna.
Aku ingin sekali mengajakmu ke Venesia, Anna.
Have you been there before, Mr. Rosso?
Pak Rosso pernah ke sana?
Yeah.
Pernah.
The music in that film is great too.
Musik di film itu juga indah.
I bet you've probably heard the theme song of the movie before too.
Aku yakin Anna pernah dengar lagu tema filmnya.
How does it go?
Seperti apa?
Let's see…
Begini…
I have an idea!
Aku punya ide!
How about we go see it now?
Bagaimana kalau kita ke bioskop?
I think we can still get in.
Sepertinya masih sempat.
Yes, but…
Boleh, tapi…
Oh, right.
Benar juga.
We'd get out late if we see it now.
Selesainya larut malam, ya.
Yeah.
Ya.
I'm back.
Aku kembali.
Oh, I'll do that.
Aku saja yang membersihkan.
It's fine.
Tak usah.
I'm sorry for taking the afternoon off from the restaurant every day.
Maaf, tiap sore aku izin dari restoran.
It's fine.
Tak apa.
There's not much going on at this hour anyway.
Jam sebegini restoran sepi.
I don't mean to pry…
Aku tak bermaksud ikut campur…
but where are you going every day?
tapi setiap hari kau ke mana?
Oh, forget I asked.
Lupakan saja.
You're free to use your free time as you wish.
Kau bebas menggunakan waktu luangmu.
Shooting practice.
Latihan menembak.
Shooting?
Menembak?
Yes, at Mr. Wenkel's shooting range.
Ya, di lapangan tembak Pak Wenkel.
Oh, you go to Wenkel's place?
Oh, di tempat Wenkel?
Yeah, he's a good guy.
Ya, dia orang baik.
Have you ever fired a gun before, Mr. Rosso?
Pak Rosso pernah menembakkan pistol?
A gun? Absolutely not.
Pistol? Tak pernah.
Just looking at one makes me tremble in fear.
Aku sudah gemetar melihatnya.
Here you go.
Silakan.
Enjoy.
Nikmatilah.
Thanks.
Terima kasih.
I wonder how it is this time.
Kali ini bagaimana, ya?
Give it a taste.
Coba cicipi.
What does it taste like?
Bagaimana rasanya?
There's garlic, olive oil, parsley, and…
Ada bawang putih, minyak zaitun, peterseli, dan…
You can't taste the other ingredients, right?
Bahan lain tak terasa, ya?
Right.
Ya.
Then it's not real pasta.
Berarti ini bukan pasta sejati.
This is tough.
Sulit, ya.
Everything comes with training.
Semuanya perlu latihan.
Mr. Rosso, you can take a bath now.
Pak Rosso, silakan kalau mau mandi.
Have a good night.
Selamat malam.
I can't believe such a film existed when I was young.
Sulit dipercaya ada film seperti ini saat aku masih muda.
Mr. Rosso, you always cried as you watched films.
Pak Rosso selalu menangis saat menonton film.
Yeah.
Ya.
I had no time to watch them when I was young, even if I wanted to.
Saat muda aku ingin menonton film, tapi tak bisa.
I ate so many delicious foods back then,
Dulu aku makan banyak hidangan enak,
but I don't remember the taste of a single dish.
tapi aku tak ingat rasanya sama sekali.
I didn't even know the taste of sugar.
Rasa gula pun aku tak ingat.
The taste of sugar?
Rasa gula?
You know about me, right?
Kau sudah tahu tentangku, 'kan?
After you left, I looked into you as well.
Setelah kau pergi, aku juga mencari tahu tentangmu.
Nina Fortner.
Nina Fortner.
You went missing after your parents were killed by an unknown individual.
Kau hilang setelah orang tuamu dibunuh orang tak dikenal.
What did you want with me?
Apa yang kau inginkan dariku?
Did you have a job for me?
Kau butuh jasaku?
Did you want me to teach you?
Atau ingin kuajari?
I thought about having you teach me.
Aku ingin minta diajari.
How did you know about me?
Dari mana kau tahu tentangku?
There was a professor researching you at my university's law school.
Ada dosen fakultas hukum di kampusku yang menyelidikimu.
The Ristorante Nino incident.
Kasus Ristorante Nino.
The Sacco Milano incident.
Kasus Sacco Milano.
The Mr. Sabatini bomb murder incident.
Kasus pengeboman Sabatini.
Each case was a murder conducted through different means,
Kau dipanggil sebagai tersangka di ketiga kasus
and he was called as a witness.
meski modus operandinya berbeda.
But they all lacked sufficient evidence and led to no charges.
Karena kekurangan bukti, tuntutan tak dilayangkan.
However, that professor thought of an interesting theory.
Namun, dosen itu punya teori menarik.
Based on that theory,
Berdasarkan teori itu…
you were undoubtedly a professional hit man.
kau adalah pembunuh bayaran profesional.
And an elite one at that.
Bahkan, termasuk elite.
How many people do you think I've killed?
Menurutmu berapa yang sudah kubunuh?
To be honest, I don't even remember myself.
Sejujurnya, aku pun tak ingat.
It was when I was still a kid.
Awalnya saat aku masih kecil.
Before I knew it, I had joined an organization.
Tanpa sadar, aku masuk organisasi.
Stealing. Blackmail.
Mencuri. Memeras.
I'd do anything.
Apa pun kulakukan.
And in the end, I became a hit man,
Pada akhirnya, aku jadi pembunuh bayaran.
since I'd get to eat good food as a reward.
Aku bisa makan enak sebagai imbalan.
It was no big deal.
Aku tak pikir panjang.
I was working.
Bagiku itu pekerjaan semata.
It was just like any other day.
Saat itu seperti hari lainnya.
The same as always.
Tak ada bedanya.
It was a café in broad daylight.
Lokasinya kafe di siang hari.
This stranger from who knows where was my next hit out of countless others,
Orang asing yang entah dari mana itu targetku yang kesekian.
and I aimed my gun at him.
Aku membidik ke arahnya.
That stranger had ordered a coffee.
Dia sudah memesan kopi.
Then, he started putting in sugar.
Lalu, dia menambahkan gula.
One spoonful.
Satu sendok.
Two spoonfuls.
Dua sendok.
Three spoonfuls.
Tiga sendok.
Four spoonfuls.
Empat sendok.
When he put in his fifth spoonful of sugar,
Saat dia menambahkan sendokan ke lima,
the taste of the coffee I usually drink spread through my mouth.
rasa kopi yang biasa kuminum terasa di mulutku.
That stranger enjoyed it as he drank.
Dia sangat menikmati kopi itu.
So I lowered my gun.
Lalu, kuturunkan senapanku.
That's all it took.
Itu saja.
That's what made me stop killing.
Seketika aku berhenti membunuh.
For those six months,
Kenapa selama enam bulan itu,
why didn't you ask me to teach you how to kill?
kau tak minta diajari cara membunuh?
Because…
Karena
I felt that I shouldn't drag you into this.
rasanya aku tak boleh melibatkanmu.
Do you absolutely have to go?
Haruskah kau pergi?
Goodbye.
Selamat tinggal.
Thank you, Mr. Rosso.
Terima kasih, Pak Rosso.
Killing someone is simple.
Membunuh seseorang itu mudah.
All you need to do is forget the taste of sugar.
Kau tinggal melupakan rasa gula.